Register of the John Davis Lodge papers, 1886-1987
Hoover Institution Archives
- Photographs, 1932-1985 (Photo file)
  - 84 prints portraying John D. Lodge during his Governorship of Connecticut, 1950-1954 (Envelope AA-AD)
    Includes 1 print of Mr. and Mrs. Dwight Eisenhower; 1 print of the USS Coral Sea; 2 prints of the 1950 campaign; 7 prints of the 1954 campaign; 5 prints of Lodge's inauguration; 1 print of Mrs. Lodge and Richard Nixon; and 1 print each of Lodge with Governor John Volpe and Liberian Under-Secretary of State Momolu Dukuly.
  - Portrayals of John D. Lodge during his Ambassadorship to Spain, 1955-1961
    - 170 prints (Envelope AE-AG)
      Includes 71 prints of Mallorca, Junipero Serra's birthplace; 23 prints of Lodge and Spanish Foreign Minister Fernando Maria Castiella; 1 print of Mr. and Mrs. Lodge with Clare Boothe Luce; 1 print of Lodge and Richard Nixon; and 16 prints of Lodge and Foreign Minister Castiella signing the 1960 Agriculture Agreement between Spain and the United States.
    - 168 prints (Envelope AH-AI)
      Includes 92 prints of Lodge's visit to Arevalo, Spain; 5 prints of the European Chiefs of Mission Conference in Paris; 12 prints of the International Conference on Civil Service Training in Madrid; and 34 prints of Lodge attending an American Chamber of Commerce banquet in Barcelona.
    - 134 prints (Envelope AJ-AK)
      Includes 26 prints of Admiral George Anderson and Francisco Franco; 44 prints of the recommissioning of the Legazpi; and 28 prints of United States Press Secretary James Hagerty's visit to Madrid.
    - 154 prints (Envelope AL-AO)
      Includes 2 prints of President Eisenhower's visit to Spain, 1959; 2 prints of Major General S.J. Donovan, Major General H.K. Mooney and Lodge; 38 prints of the Lodge's tour of Spain, 1959; 37 prints of the recommissioning of the Princesa; and 17 prints of General Donovan and Lodge at San Javier.
    - 47 prints (Envelope AP)
      Includes 21 prints of the United States House members of the Subcommittee on Foreign Operations and Subcommittee on International Operations with Generalissimo Franco; 2 prints of Lodge with Maj. Gen. A. P. O'meara, Maj. Gen. S. J. Donovan and Brig. Gen. Royal Reynolds.
    - 132 prints (Envelope AQ-AS)
      Includes 2 prints of Lodge and Second Secretary Lyle Lane; 2 prints of the Henry Cabot Lodge, Sr. bronze; 45 prints of the Barcelona International Samples Fair, 1959; 1 print of Bob Wilson; and 7 prints of a 1959 press conference.
    - 105 prints (Envelope AT-AV)
      Includes 36 prints of various receptions attended by the Lodges; 39 prints of John D., Francesca, Lily and Beatrice Lodge; and 11 prints of the Minister of Foreign Affairs Castiella, Secretary of State John Foster Dulles, Spanish Ambassador to the United States Jose Maria de Areilza, Count of Motrico and John D. Lodge.
    - 99 prints (Envelope AW-AZ)
      Also includes 69 prints of Ezra Taft Benson; 7 prints of Maj. Gen. August W. Kissner, Maj Gen. H.K. Mooney, Gen. Thomas S. Power, and John D. Lodge; and 28 prints of Secretary Neil McElroy's visit with Generalissimo Franco, Minister of Foreign Affairs Castiella, Minister of the Army Lt. Gen. Barroso and Lodge.
    - 141 prints (Envelope BA-BC)
      Includes 11 prints of Lodge with Spanish Minister of Agriculture Don Cirilo Canovas; 1 print of Mrs. Lodge with Italian Ambassador Duquesa de Sueca; and 46 prints of Mrs. Lodge and Beatrice at the hospital of Asilo de San Rafael.
    - 236 prints (Envelope BD-BH)
      Includes 1 print of Givon Parson, Robert Cavanaugh, Lodge, Gerald Warner, and Richard Courtenaye; 19 prints of the Elizondo Radar Site; 8 prints of Cardinal Francis Spellman; 45 prints of the USS McGowan; and 31 unidentified prints.
    - 116 prints (Envelope BI-BK)
      Includes 4 prints of Lodge with Generalissimo Franco; 19 prints of Lodge's appointment to the Municipal Palace of Culture; 12 prints of Lodge with Prescott Bush; 7 prints of Lodge with the House of Representatives Committee on Operations; and 19 prints of Lodge's presentation of the Medal of Freedom to Madame Eugenie Duport.
    - 37 prints (Envelope BL)
      Includes 6 prints of Mr. and Mrs. Skelton; 7 prints of under-secretary Minister of the Presidency Luis Carrero Blanco, Foreign Minister Castiella and Lodge; and 9 prints of Lodge at the "El Carmen de los Martires,; Granada.
    - 47 prints (Envelope BM-BN)
      Includes 1 print of Lodge with Minister and Deputy Chief of Mission, Homer Byington; 1 print of Lodge with Admiral Charles P. Brown, Commander of the U.S. Sixth Fleet; 12 prints of the Center for North American Studies in Valencia; and 24 prints of Senator Hubert Humphrey's visit to Madrid.
    - 62 prints (Envelope BO-BQ)
      Includes 7 prints of Lodge with Count yof Mayalde, mayor of Madrid; 2 prints of Lodge awarding Antonio Ubarrechena the Medal of Freedom; 10 prints of the Center for North American Studies in Valencia; 1 print of Foreign Affairs Minister Castiella; 11 prints of Lodge at the School of Industrial Organization, and 1 print of Robert Michel.
    - 60 prints (Envelope BR-BS)
      Includes 13 prints of Lodge with Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr., Spanish Amb. to the U.N. Jose Felix de Lequerica, Spanish Minister of Foreign Affairs Alberto Martin Artajo and Minister of Commerce Manuel Arburua; 6 prints of Lionel Hampton in Madrid; 1 print of the USS Forrestal; and 24 prints of the Citizens Advisory Committee's inspection of air bases.
    - 67 prints (Envelope BT-BV)
      Includes 2 prints of Commandante Benito receiving the Legion of Merit Award; 3 prints of Beatrice Lodge; 4 prints of Admiral Crommelin, Admiral Fernandez de Bobadilla, and Lodge; 6 prints of Lodge and Minister of Foreign Affairs Artajo; and 27 prints of the Barcelona International Samples Fair, 1956.
    - 62 prints (Envelope BW-BY)
      Includes 2 prints of Lt. Gen. Eduardo Gouyaley receiving the Legion of Merit Award; 11 prints of the Barcelona International Samples Fair, 1956; 1 print of Lodge with Jose Luis de la Pena of Diario Informaciones; 7 prints of Lodge with Foreign Minister Artajo; 1 print of Count Godo; and 16 prints of Beatrice as Queen of the Fiesta de la Vendimia.
    - 73 prints (Envelope BZ)
      Includes 5 prints of Minister of Foreign Affairs Alberto Artajo, Sec. of State John F. Dulles, Lodge and Generalissimo Franco; 3 prints of Lodge and Spanish Red Cross Pres. Martinez de Tena; 58 prints of Lodge at Zaragoya; and 2 prints of Mrs. Lodge with Generalissimo Franco and his wife.
    - 46 prints (Envelope CA-CD)
      Includes 2 prints of the Joint Committee on Atomic Energy with Gen. Kissner and Senators Bricker and Anderson; 15 prints of the Lodge's Presentation of Credentials; 14 prints of Sec. Neil McElroy's visit to Madrid; and 1 print of Pope John XXIII with Mr. and Mrs. Lodge and Beatrice.
    - 197 prints (Envelope CE-CG)
      Includes 29 prints of Lodge and Sec. of the Navy Thomas S. Gates; 12 prints of Admiral Arleigh A. Burke and Lodge; 27 prints of Sec. of Air James H. Douglas; 7 prints of the Director General of Instruction in the Ministry of Air Gen. Jose Aviles Bascuas receiving the Legion of Merit Award.
    - 97 prints (Envelope CH-CI)
      Includes 11 prints of Minister of Army Antonio Barroso and President of the Cortes Esteban Bilbao; 2 prints of Lodge, Vice-Adm. E.C Ekstrom, Capt. Hale, and Capt. Collett; 15 prints of Minister of Foreign Affairs Castiella and John S. Burgess, Agricultural Attache; and 16 prints of Deputy Sec. of Defense Donald Quarles.
    - 87 prints (Envelope CJ-CL)
      Includes 5 prints of Jose Maria de Areilza, County Motrcio; 25 prints of Commander W.R. Anderson and the USS Nautilus; 3 prints of Generalissimo Franco and the Pres. of the Nuclear Energy Board at the opening of the Juan Vigon National Nuclear Energy Center; and 8 prints of Lodge and Vice-Adm. Charles Brown.
    - 83 prints (Envelope CM-CP)
      Includes 10 prints of Representative Donald Jackson's visit to Madrid; 1 print of Lodge with Brig. General Royal Reynolds, Jr., and Brig. Gen. C.A. Dahlen; and 3 prints of Vice Chief of Staff Gen. Curtis LeMay; 8 prints of Minister of Foreign Affairs Fernando Castiella.
    - 77 prints (Envelope CQ-CS)
      Includes 50 prints of the Barcelona International Samples Fair, 1958; 1 print of the Count of Motrico and William Smedberg, III; 2 prints of Thomas Dewart; 2 prints of the board of the American Embassy Personnel Association; and 7 prints of Lodge at the Caritas Mattress Program Ceremony.Includes 50 prints of the Barcelona International Samples Fair, 1958; 1 print of the Count of Motrico and William Smedberg, III; 2 prints of Thomas Dewart; 2 prints of the board of the American Embassy Personnel Association; and 7 prints of Lodge at the Caritas Mattress Program Ceremony.
  - 75 prints portraying John D. Lodge and his activities, 1961-1969 (Envelope CT-CV)
    Includes 1 print of the National Federation of Republican Women; 2 prints of Lodge attending a Chowder and Marching Club meeting; 6 prints of Lodge's participation in the 1968 Presidential Campaign; and 1 print of William Rentschler.
  - 228 prints portraying John D. Lodge during his Ambassadorship to Argentina, 1969-1974 (Envelope CZ-DC)
    Includes circa 30 prints of Sec. William Rogers' visit to Argentina; 4 prints of Lodge and Amb. Ernest Siracusa; 3 prints of Lodge and Alejandro Orfila; 6 prints of Robert Michel; 1 print of lodge and Nixon.
  - 168 prints portraying John D. Lodge during his Ambassadorship to Argentina, 1969-1974 (Envelope DD-DI)
    Includes 1 print of William Dohery of the American Institute for Free Labor Development; 1 print of the Minister of Economics Dr. Jose Maria Dagnino Pastore, 1 print of Foreign Minister Juan B. Martin; 30 prints of Sec. of Trade Dr. Elvio Bardinelli; 9 prints of Lodge's Presentation of Credentials; and 7 prints of Lodge's Swearing-in-Ceremony.
  - 92 prints portraying John D. Lodge during his activities, 1974-1979 (Envelope DJ-DL)
    Includes 3 prints of Bob Hope; 5 prints of Amb. John Humes and Arthur Kaufman; 9 prints of the Eisenhower Foundation Award to Lodge; 1 print of Argentine Amb. to the U.S. Jorge Espil and Robert Hill; 2 prints of Alberto Herce Consul General of Spain; and 3 prints of Gerald Ford and his wife.
  - 78 prints portraying John D. Lodge during his Ambassadorship to Switzerland, 1983-1985 (Envelope DM-DN)
    Includes 5 prints of Lodge's Swearing-in-Ceremony with Chief Justice Warren Burger; 1 print of Lodge in Pres. Reagan's office; 1 negative of Admiral Andrew; 2 prints of Lodge and Kenneth Davis; 5 prints of Lodge and Reagan; 1 print of Reagan and Bush; and 3 prints of Lodge with Herman Levy.
  - 139 prints portraying John D. Lodge during his Ambassadorship to Switzerland, 1983-1985 (Envelope DO-DQ)
    Includes 1 print of William Baldridge; 1 print of Governor John Connolly; 16 prints of Lodge's medals; 1 print of Charles Wick; 9 prints of the signing of the deed for the Chancery Building; 1 print of the Iraqi Amb. Riyadh Ali Ali-Azzawi; 3 prints of King Gustav and Queen Sylvia of Sweden; and 1 print of the Lodges with Vice President Bush.
  - 64 prints portraying John D. Lodge during his Governorship of Connecticut, 1950-1955 (Envelope fDR)
  - 91 prints portraying John D. Lodge during his Ambassadorship to Argentina, 1969-1974 (Envelope fDS)
  - Approximately 60 prints illustrating the christening of the USS Nautilus (Envelope fDT)
  - Approximately 262 prints portraying John D. Lodge during his Governorship of Connecticut, 1950-1955 (Envelope fDU-fDX)
  - 1 print of the Ukrainian Congress Committee of America, 1974 (Envelope mDY)
- Incremental Sound Recordings, 1952-1973 (Boxes 312-315)
  Speeches and interviews relating to American politics and foreign relations.
- Incremental Motion Picture Film, 1969-1973 (Boxes 316-318)
  J. D. Lodge performing ambassadorial functions in Argentina.